BABAJIDE SAMUEL WILLIAMS

Email: babanila@yahoo.com Phone: +4917630172022

GitHub Link: https://github.com/Babanila Skype: al.babanila

Linkedln: https://linkedin.com/babanila

I'm a solution-driven software engineer with over 10 years of experience in the IT world, providing a permanent solution to day-to-day challenges that can give the company a competitive edge and producing outstanding results for clients.

EDUCATION

MSc University of Applied Science Kiel

Kiel, Schleswig-Holstein, Germany. Course: Information Engineering (2020)

BSc Federal University of Technology Akure

Ondo, Nigeria.

Course: Computer Science (2010)

SOFTWARE SKILLS

- Programming Languages and frameworks (Vanilla JavaScript, Typescript, Nodejs, React, Nextjs, Gatsbyjs, Hugojs, Coffee Script, GraphQL, Storybook, Content Magement System(Contentful, Sanity Studio), Python, SQL, CSS, HTML, Cypress, Jest, Mocha).
- Git, Test Driven Development, Unit Test, End-to-End Test, Continuous Integration / Continuous Development, Automation Testing (Circle CI, Travis, Netlify), Message Queue (Google PubSub).

WORK EXPERIENCE

HealthHero GmbH

Position: Senior Frontend Engineer

Sept. 2021 – till date

EGEOS GmbH

Position: Frontend Developer Oct. 2020 –Sept. 2021

RESPONSIBILTIES

- Creating advance software solutions and web applications using React, TypeScript, JavaScript, Node.js, HTML, CSS3, Cypress, Jest, Storybook.
- Creating UI components library.
- Enhance user experience by adding user accessibility to websites.
- Optimization of websites.
- Developed Long-Covid-App
- Developed Questionnaire Rule Engine tool.
- Creating software solutions and different web applications for clients using frameworks and technologies like React, Gatsby, Hugo, JavaScript, Nodejs, HTML and CSS3.
- Optimization of websites.
- Adding highly reusable new features, fixing bugs

and also maintaining the company code-base at large.

Daizu GmbH

Position: Software Engineer June 2019 – June 2020

Commercetools GmbH

Position: Software Engineer June 2018 – May 2019

Bliss Energy Nig. Ltd.

Position: Software Developer May 2015 – May. 2018

Emirates Flight Catering Position: System Admin.
Dec. 2012 – Mar. 2015

Yemshba Telephone Network Position: NetworkAdmin.
Mar. 2010 – Sept. 2012

Developed questionnaire app, e-commerce, CRM and blog-post website using using technologies such as React, Gatsby, GraphQL, CMS(Sanity), JavaScript, HTML, style-components and pure CSS.

- Developed innovative api solutions using Nodejs, CoffeeScript, REST, GraphQL to build different modules that supports modern microservice-based architecture for clients (e.g. Category Export, Resource Deleter etc.).
- Developed full websites and website pages for different clients.
- Wrote end-to-end tests for apis.
- Developed innovative software solutions using different web technologies such as JavaScript, Node.js, HTML, CSS.
- Developed different website using pure vanila javascript, jQuery, React, HTML, CSS.
- Play an instrumental role in the setting up of network which enhances the development and growth of the company.
- Initiate market research studies to identify demand for company products or services; similarly, capture business development opportunities and capitalize on the same.
- Setting up and maintaining of window sever 2012.
- Maintain of routers and switches configured during the setting up of network.
- Creating, controlling and maintaining of Users account while carrying out installation, updating, upgrading and maintaining software installed on office equipment like computer systems, routers, switches.
- Setting up and maintaining of window sever 2008.
- Creating, Controlling and maintaining of Users account
- Installation, updating, upgrading and maintaining software installed on company systems.
- Installation, updating and maintaining of Office equipment like computer Systems, routers, switches